# Fernando Felicíssimo

Dublin, Ireland

Contact details: +353 83039 6499 / ffelicissimo@gmail.com

Linked in

**Objective** 

Infrastructure Analyst / Infrastructure Architect / Devops

Summary

IT Professional with 17 years of experience across various industries such as Retail, Healthcare, Medias, Internet Provider and Telecom, with proven background successfully managing all facets of site development, from initial design and architecture to site deployment and client management.

Demonstrated ability to complete high-end projects in deadline-oriented environments and successfully revamped Web sites to enhance user satisfaction and retention time, streamline navigation, and increase ad revenue and sales.

### Computer Skills:

- Webservices: Jboss, Tomcat, Apache, Nginx, HAPROXY, WebSphere, Node
- Oracle Middleware: WebLogic, Oracle Service Bus and SOA
- Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Mongodb, Postgree
- Virtualization: Esx, Esxi, Vmware, Vcenter, Oracle Vmware
- Microservices: Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher
- Operating System: Linux Systems (Redhat, Oracle, Ubuntu, Centos, Debian)
- Automatization and Building: python, vagrant, ansible, maven, Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CircleCl), Blue Green Agreements, Agile Development
- Web Applications: Java, NodeJS, PHP

# **Professional Experience**

### 07/2011 - 05/2017

### Linux Sysadmin / Infrastructure Architect / Devops

Magazine Luiza (LuizaLabs) - São Paulo - BR (Industry: Retail)

I helped transition the company's conventional infrastructure based ITIL on to modernization and digitization of IT processes, working with some public clouding providers (AWS, GCP and AZZURE) and new technologies for Infrastructure as a Code (vagrant, ansible, python, git) using the Lean IT concept with agile model development.

I contributed as a technical leader on 5 major projects:

- Portal Luiza Portal Luiza is an intranet portal for employees that has several tools coupled to one of them and access to salary information.
- Mastersaf NFE v1 generation and sending Electronic Invoice to the Brazilian Government.
- Mastersaf NFE v2 New Architecture and Infrastructure in Middleware.
- Docker implementation of PAAS environment in Docker using Rancher. I created all Docker environment automation using the code repository (GitHub, Bitbucket), continuous integration (CircleCI, Jenkins) and continuous delivery (CircleCI, Jenkins) running both health tests of code and build automation (Maven) in datacenter on premise.
- Kubernetes Implementation of cluster K8s in datacenter on premise.

#### 05/ 2009 - 06/2011

### Linux/Windows Sysadmin

Unimed – São José dos Campos – BR (Industry: Healthcare)

As a technical leader I had 4 major projects, the main benefits for the company were increased security, high availability of products and services online and redundancy of connectivity with its subsidiaries:

- Redundancy of internet services (Edge Firewall (IPTABLES), BGP, NIC BR).
- Redundancy of connectivity of the physical presence points.
- Architecture and implantation SAE (Electronic Authorization System) external medical agreements.
- VPN and DMZ.

# **Technical Support Analyst**

- 2008 2009: Abril Medias Franca BR
- 2000 2004: Francanet Internet Provider Sao Paulo BR

### Internship

2004 - 2004: CTBC Telecom - São Paulo - BR

## Courses and Training

2008 LPI Level I and II Certification preparation course

> At 4Linux, São Paulo, Duration: 240 hours.

Basic IPV6 2011

> At NIC.BR, São Paulo Duration: 32 hours.

2013 Power VM administration

Conducted in house by HP, Franca

Duration: 40 hours.

2015 Clouding Computing Architect (AWS)

At SOA EXPER, São Paulo Duration: 120 hours.

2016 Docker

At InfoSlack, Virtual training

Duration: 20 hours.

**Education** 

07/2017 to date English as Foreigner Language – (level A1)

ISI, Dublin

2003 - 2005Bachelor in Telecommunication Technology

University of Franca

Other details

References available upon request.

Visa sponsorship required.